[
  {
    "question" : "It is often a straightforward proposition to determine the performance of a system as a function of its parameters.",
    "a" : "Large versus systems",
    "b" : "Nonlinear versus linear",
    "c" : "Design",
    "d" : "Sensitivity analysis",
    "e" : "None of the above",
    "answer" : 3
  },
  {
    "question" : "This is the discrepancy between an exact value and some approximation to it.",
    "a" : "Round-off errors",
    "b" : "Total numerical error",
    "c" : "Truncation error",
    "d" : "Approximation error",
    "e" : "None of the above",
    "answer" : 4
  },

  {
    "question" : "This is the summation of the truncation and round-off errors.",
    "a" : "Round-off errors",
    "b" : "Total numerical error",
    "c" : "Truncation error",
    "d" : "Approximation error",
    "e" : "None of the above",
    "answer" : 2
  },

  {
    "question" : "_________ refers to how closely a computed or measured value agrees with the true value.",
    "a" : "Precision",
    "b" : "True value",
    "c" : "Accuracy",
    "d" : "Round-off errors",
    "e" : "None of the above",
    "answer" : 3
  },

  {
    "question" : "It is a special type of software that allows the user to enter and perform calculations on rows and columns of data.",
    "a" : "Excel",
    "b" : "Matlab",
    "c" : "Mathcad",
    "d" : "Gitlab",
    "e" : "None of the above",
    "answer" : 1
  },
  {
    "question" : "If the true value of a measurement is 10.9 cm and the approximate value is 10.7 cm, what is the true error?",
    "a" : "0.2 cm",
    "b" : "1.8 cm",
    "c" : "0.2 %",
    "d" : "1.8 %",
    "e" : "None of the above",
    "answer" : 1
  },
  {
    "question" : "If the true value of a measurement is 10.9 cm and the approximate value is 10.7 cm, what is the true relative error:",
    "a" : "0.2 cm",
    "b" : "1.8 cm",
    "c" : "0.2 %",
    "d" : "1.8 %",
    "e" : "None of the above",
    "answer" : 4
  },
  {
    "question" : "Solving the function f(x)=4x3-15x2+17x+6 using the Newton-Raphson method with a starting value of x = 0, the first iteration yields a value of x equal to:",
    "a" : "0.3529",
    "b" : "- 0.3529",
    "c" : "6",
    "d" : "17",
    "e" : "None of the above",
    "answer" : 3
  },
  {
    "question" : "Using Bairstowâ€™s method to solve the roots of the equation f(x) = x^4 - x - 10 with starting values r = 0.1 and s = 0.1, the first iteration yields:",
    "a" : "r = 1.251, s = 0.113",
    "b" : "r = - 3.145, s = 4.678",
    "c" : "r = 1.315, s = 5.278",
    "d" : "r = - 7.364, s = 13.579",
    "e" : "None of the above",
    "answer" : 4
  },
  {
    "question" : "To solve the roots of the equation f(x)=4x^5-7x^2+8x-2 using simple fixed point iteration and initial value of x = 0.5 , which of the following formulations is converging?",
    "a" : "x=4x^5-7x^2+9x-2",
    "b" : "x=((7x^2-8x+2)/4)^(1/5)",
    "c" : "x=(7x^2-8x+2)/x^4",
    "d" : "x=((4x^5-7x^2-2)/(-8)",
    "e" : "None of the above",
    "answer" : 3
  }

]